Guide to the Donald Gordon Papers, 1900-1988 UA.90.F46
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Ernst Ludwig Kirchner, I.
  - Inventory of Kirchner Works, 1.
    - Seated Dancer; Woman with Evening Dress (Sitzende Tänzerin; Frau im Abendkleid), 239, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Kneeling Nude before Red Screen (Kniender Mädchenakt vor rotem Wandschirm), 240, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Berlin, Zoo (Tiergarten, Berlin), 241, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Castle on Fehmarn (Berg auf Fehmarn), 242, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Mexico Bay, Fehmarn (Mexikobucht auf Fehmarn), 243, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Three Girls with Boat in a Storm (Drei Mädchen mit Boot in Brandung), 244, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Nude Reclining on the Beach (Liegendes Mädchen am Strande), 245, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Girl in the Suthwester (Mädchen in Südwester), 246, 1912/1920 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Lady with Red Hat on the Shore (Dame am Meer sitzend mit rotem Hut), 247, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Trees above Sandy Path (Bäume über Sandweg), 248, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Small Fehmarn Coast Scene (Kleine Fehmarnküste), 249, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Lighthouse behind Dune (Leuchtturm hinter Bucht), 249, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Green Lighthouse on Fehmarn (Grüner Leuchtturm auf Fehmarn), 251, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Staberhuck Beacon Fehmarn (Leuchtturm Staberhuck, Fehmarn), 252, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Lighthouse (Leuchtturm), 253, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Sailboats in a Storm (Segelboote im Sturm), 254, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Two Female Nudes under Trees (Zwei weibliche Akte unter Bäumen), 255, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Bather between Rocks (Badende zwischen Steine), 256, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Two Bathers on the Shore with Bark (Zwei badende Frauen am Strand mit Barke), 257, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Three Bathers by the Sea (Drei Badende am Meer), 258, 1912/1920 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Three Bathers among Rocks (Drei Badende zwischen Stenen), 259, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Brown Nude at the Window (Brauner Akt am Fenster), 260, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Two Nudes by a Tree, Fehmarn (Zwei Akte an einem Baum, Fehmarn), 261, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Striding into the Sea (Ins Meer Schreitende), 262, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Nudes in the Forest (Akte im Wald), 263, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Coast of Fehmarn in Horizontal Format (Fehmarnküste in Querformat), 264, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Nude with Hat on the Shore (Akt mit Hut am Strand), 265, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Two Bathers, Fehmarn (Zwei Badende, Fehmarn), 266, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Standing Nude Before Sand-Dune (Stehender weiblicher Akt vor Bucht), 267, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Seated Woman with Wood Sculpture (Sitzende Frau mit Holzplastik), 268, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Still Life with Glasses (Stilleben mit Gläsern), 269, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Still Life with Duck and Snipes (Stilleben mit Ente und Schnepfen), 270, 1912/1920 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Still Life with Gulls, Poppies, and Strawberries (Stilleben mit Möven, Mohn, Erdbeeren), 271, 1912/1920 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Seagull Hunter in the Woods (Mövenjäger im Gehölz), 272, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Houses with Dovecote (Häuser mit Taubenschlag), 273, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Suburb of Berlin (Vorort Berlin), 274, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Red Elisabeth Riverbank, Berlin (Rotes Elisabethufer, Berlin), 275, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Woman with Dark Veil (Frauenporträt mit dunklem Schleir), 276, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Lady in the Park (Blaue Dame im Tiergarten), 277, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Reclining Nude (Liegender Akt), 278, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Woman with High Collar (Frau mit großem Kragen), 279, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Woman in a Green Blouse (Frau in grüner Jacke), 280, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Nude in Interior (Akt in Innenraum), 281, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Seated Nude in Studio (Sitzender Amt im Atelier), 282, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Still Life with Glass Pitcher (Stilleben mit Glaskrug), 283, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Still Life with Pears (Stilleben mit Birnen), 284, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Couple in Room (Paar im Zimmer), 285, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Three Models (Drei Modelle), 286 / Contortinist with Clown (Schlangenmensch mit Clown), 286v, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - In the Brothel (Im Bordell), 287, 1912/1920 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Girl Circus Rider (Zirkusreiterin), 288 / Nude on Wheeled Bed (Akt auf Rollbett), 288v, 1912/1910 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Female Nude with Bathtub (Weiblicher Akt mit Badezimmer), 289, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Portrait of Dr. Alfred Döblin (Porträt Dr. Alfred Döblin), 290, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Nollendorf Square (Nollendorfplatz), 291, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Street in Schöneberg City Park; Innsburck Street (Straße am Stadtpark Schöneberg; Innsbrucker Straße), 292 / Seated Nude, Drawing (Sitzender Akt, Zeichnung), 292v, 1912-1913/ 1904-1906 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Two Nudes in a Shallow Tub (Zwei nackte Mädchen in flacher Wanne), 293 / Boats on the Elbe in Front of Yellow Houses, Dresden (Elbkähne vor gelben Häusern, Dresden), 293v, 1912-1913/1920 / 1909 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Two Girls Conversing (Zwei plaudernde Mädchen), 294, 1912-1913/ 1920 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Two Women with Washbasin (Zwei Frauen mit Waschbecken), 295, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Otto Mueller with Pipe (Otto Mueller mit Pfeife), 296, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Self-Portrait (Selbstbildnis), 297, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Sick Woman; Woman with Hat (Kranke Frau; Dame mit Hut), 298, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Three Dancers (drei Tänzerinnen), 299, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Artists' Conversation (Unterhaltung der Künstler), 300, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Artist Sketching with Two Women; Artists (Skizzierender Künstler mit Zzwei Frauen; Künstlergruppe), 301, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Erich Heckel and Otto Mueller Playing Chess (Erich Heckel und Otto Mueller beim Schach), 302, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - Erich Heckel and Otto Mueller Playing Chess II (Erich Heckel und Otto Mueller beim Schach II), 303, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Woman with Raised Skirt (Frau mit erhobenem Rock), 304, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - Halle Gate, Berlin (Hallesches Tor, Belrin), 305, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Yellow Angelbank, Berlin (Gelbes Engelufer, Berlin), 306, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Burgstaaken Harbor, Fehmarn (Hafen Burgstaaken, Fehmarn), 307, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - Boat Harbor on Fehmarn (Bootshafen auf Fehmarn), 308, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Curved Dock (Gebogener Landungssteg), 309, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - Fehmarn Windmill (Windmühle auf Fehmarn), 310, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - The Toilette; Woman before the Mirror (Toilette; Frau vor dem Spiegel), 311, 1913/1920 (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - Tower Rom; Self-Portrait with Erna (Turmzimmer; Selbstbildnis mit Erna), 312, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - Tea at Fehmarn (Fehmarntee), 313, 1913/1920 (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - Forest Promenade (Waldspaziergang), 314, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - Woman with Goats by the Sea (Frau mit Ziegen am Meer), 315, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - Erna near the Sea, Fehmarn (Erna am Meer, Fehmarn), 316, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - Erna with Japanese Umbrella; Japanese Girl (Erna mit Japanschirm, Japanerin), 317, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - Couple Under Japanese Umbrella (Paar unter Japanschirm), 318, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 94)
    - In the Hammock (In der Hängematte), 319, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 94)
    - Tree in the Dunes (Baum in den Dünen), 320, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - Landscape with Chestnut Tree (Landschaft mit Kastanienbaum), 321, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 96)
    - Staberhof Countryseat, Fehmarn I (Gut Staborhof, Fehmarn I), 322, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 97)
    - Staberhof Countryseat II (Gut Staberhof II), 323, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 98)
    - Staberhof Countryseat III (Gut Staberhof III), 324, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 99)
    - Fehmarn Coast with Lighthouse (Fehmarnküste mit Leuchtturm), 325, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 100)
    - Fehmarn Lighthouse (Leutchturm auf Fehmarn), 326, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 101)
    - Fehmarn Landscape with Lighthouse (Fehmarnlandschaft mit Leutchturm), 327, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 102)
    - Fehmarn Coast (Fehmarnküste), 330, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 103)
    - Fehmarn Coastal Landscape (Küstenlandschaft Fehmarn), 331, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 104)
    - Laburnum Tree (Goldregenbaum), 332, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 105)
    - Dunes and Sea, Fehmarn (Dünen und Meer, Fehmarn), 333, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 106)
    - Large Fehmarn Coast (Große Fehmarnküste), 334, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 107)
    - Fehmarn Bay (Fehmarnbuchrt), 335, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 108)
    - Bay Coast, Fehmarn (Bucht an der Fehmarnküste), 336, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 109)
    - Pink Sun over Fehmarn Bay (Rosa Sonne über Meeresbucht, Fehmarn), 337, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 110)
    - Storm on the Fehmarn Coast (Sturm an der Fehmarnküste), 338, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 111)
    - Forest Interior with Pink Foreground (Waldinneres mit rosa Vordergrund), 339, 1913/1920 (Box 2, Folder 112)
    - Forest by the Sea (Seewald), 340, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 113)
    - House Between the Trees, Fehmarn (Haus unter Bäumen, Fehmarn), 341, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 114)
    - Group of Bathers on the Beach (Gruppe Badender am Strand), 342, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 115)
    - Nude Coming from the Forest (Aus dem Wald schreitender Akt), 343, 1913/1920 (Box 2, Folder 116)
    - Three Bathers on the Shore (Drei Badende am Strand), 344, 1913/1920 (Box 2, Folder 117)
    - Bathers in the Dunes, Fehmarn (Badende zwischen Dünen, Fehmarn), 345, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 118)
    - Bathers (Badende), 346, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 119)
    - Red Nudes (Rote Akte), 347, 1913/1925 (Box 2, Folder 120)
    - Two Nude Girls, Fehmarn (Zwei Mädchenakte, Fehmarn), 348, 1913/1920 (Box 2, Folder 121)
    - Four Bathers among the Rocks by the Sea (Vier Badende zwischen Steinem am Meer), 349, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 122)
    - Bathers at the Shore (Badende am Strand), 350, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 123)
    - Nude Youth and Girl on the Beach (Nackter Jüngling und Mädchen am Strand), 351 / Two Nudes in a Room (Zwei Akte im Raum), 351v, 1913 / 1914 (Box 2, Folder 124)
    - Two Bathers among Trees, Fehmarn (Zwei Badende zwischen Bäumen, Fehmarn), 352, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 125)
    - Five Bathers on Fehmarn (Fünf Badende auf Fehmarn), 353, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 126)
    - Three Nudes under Trees (Drei Akte unter Bäumen), 354, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 127)
    - Four Nudes under Trees (Vier Akte unter Bäumen), 355, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 128)
    - Three Bathers (Drei Badende), 356, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 129)
    - Bathers under Trees (Badende unter Bäumen), 357, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 130)
    - Bathers on Fehmarn Shore (Badende am Strand von Fehmarn), 358, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 131)
    - Red Tree on the Shore (Roter Baum am Strand), 359, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 132)
    - Judgement of Paris (Urteil des Paris), 360 / Five Bathers on a Rock (Fünf Badende an einem Stein), 360v, 1913 / 1913 (Box 2, Folder 133)
    - Nude Woman Combing her Hair (Sich kämmender Akt), 361 / Purple Trees (Violette Bäume), 361v, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 134)
    - Five Women on the Street (Fünf Frauen auf der Straße), 362, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 135)
    - Berlin Street Scene (Berliner Straßenszene), 363 / Trees (Bäume), 363v, 1913 / 1912 (Box 2, Folder 136)
    - The Street (Die Straße), 364 / Two Female Nudes, Moritzburg (Zwei Akte, Moritzburg), 364v, 1913 / 1909 (Box 2, Folder 137)
    - Street Scene (Straßenszene), 365, 1914/1922 (Box 2, Folder 138)
    - Street with Red Cocotte (Straße mit roter Kokotte), 366, 1914/1925 (Box 2, Folder 139)
    - Friedrich Street, Berlin (Friedrichstraße, Berlin), 367, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 140)
    - Leipzig Street with Electric Tram; Small Street Scene (Leipziger Straße mit Elektrischer Bahn; Kleines Stadtbild), 368, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 141)
    - Two Women on the Street (Zwei Frauen auf der Straße), 369 / Two Bathers in Surf (Zwei Badende in Wellen), 369v, 1914 / 1912 (Box 2, Folder 142)
    - Potsdam Square Berlin (Potsdamer Platz, Berlin), 370, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 143)
    - Belle Alliance Place, Berlin (Belle-Alliance-Platz, Berlin), 371, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 144)
    - Belle Alliance Place II (Belle-Alliance-Platz II), 372, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 145)
    - Coffee House (Kaffeehaus), 373, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 146)
    - Woman in Cafe (Damen im Cafe), 374, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 147)
    - Gerda, Half-Length Portrait (Frauenkopf, Gerda), 375, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 148)
    - Portrait of Gewecke (Bildnis Gewecke), 376 / Erna with Cigarette (Erna mit Zigarette), 376v, 1914 / 1913-1914 (Box 2, Folder 149)
    - Erna with Light Colored Veil (Erna mit helem Schleier), 377, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 150)
    - Bridge over the Railroad (Eisenbahnüberführung), 378, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 151)
    - Elavated Train and Railroad (Straßenbahn und Eisenbahn), 379 / Landscape of Dunes and Sea (Dünenlandschaft), 379v, 1914 / 1912 (Box 2, Folder 152)
    - View from the Window (Blick aus dem Fenster), 380, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 153)
    - Wannsee Train seen through the Studio Window (Wannseebahn durch das Atelierfesnter gesehen), 381, 1914/1926 (Box 2, Folder 154)
    - Circus Rider (Zirkusreiter), 382, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 155)
    - Blue Trapeze Artists (Blaue Artisten), 383 / Tennis Players (Tennisspielerinnen), 383v, 1914 / 1913 (Box 2, Folder 156)
    - Traveling Circus with Open-Air Arena (Wanderzirkus mit Freiluftarena), 384, 1914/1920 (Box 2, Folder 157)
    - Gas Tanks and Suburban Railway (Gaskessel und Vorortbahn), 385, 1914/1920 (Box 2, Folder 158)
    - Sailboats near Grünau (Segelboote bei Grünau), 386 / Landscape with Hill and Treees (Landschaft mit Hügel und Bäumen), 386v, 1914 / 1909 (Box 2, Folder 159)
    - Rhine River Bridge at Cologne (Rheinbrücke Köln), 387, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 160)
    - Dancing School (Tanzschule), 388, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 161)
    - Dancing Couple (Tanzpaar), 389, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 162)
    - Cafe Chantant (Tingeltangel), 390, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 163)
    - Two Red Dancers (Zwei rote Tänzerinnen), 391, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 164)
    - Dancing Girl (Tänzerin), 392, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 165)
    - The Tent; Interior in Berlin Studio (Das Zelt), 393, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 166)
    - Women at Tea-Time; Sick Woman (Frauen beim Tee; die Kranke), 394 / Reclining Woman (Liegende Frau), 394v, 1914 / 1910 (Box 2, Folder 167)
    - Path Between Trees, Fehmarn (Weg zwischen Bäumen, Fehmarn), 395, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 168)
    - Yellow Birches (Gelbe Birken), 396 / Bathers in Fehmarn Landscape (Badende in Fehmarnlandschaft), 396v, 1914 / 1914 (Box 2, Folder 169)
    - Fehmarn Wooded Landscape (Fehmarnlandschaft mit Bäumen), 397, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 170)
    - Female Nude in the Woods (Weiblicher Akt im Grünen), 398, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 171)
    - Bathers by the Sea (Badende am Meer), 399, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 172)
    - Gerda with Hat (Gerdakopf mit Hut), 400, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 173)
    - Boy by the Sea (Knabe am Meer), 401, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 174)
    - The White Beach (der weiße Strand), 402, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 175)
    - Fehmarn Moonrise (Mondaufgang auf Fehmarn), 403, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 176)
    - Bathers in the Moonlight (Badende bei Mondschein), 404, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 177)
    - Still Life with Fruit Bowl and Jars (Stillben mit Fruchtschale und Gefäßen), 405, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 178)
    - Red Still Life (Rotes Stilleben), 406, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 179)
    - Still Life with Wooden Bowl and Flowers (Stilleben mit Hozschale und Blumen), 407, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 180)
    - Tulip Blossoms (Verblühte Tulpen), 408, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 181)
    - Two Yellow Nudes with Bouquet of Flowers (Zwei gelbe Akte mit Blumenstrauß), 409, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 182)
    - Red Head (Rothaarige), 410, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 183)
    - Two Nudes in a Room (Zwei nackte Frauen im Zimmer), 411, 1914/1924 (Box 2, Folder 184)
    - Interior (Interieur), 412, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 185)
    - Landscape near Jena (Landschaft bei Jena), 413, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 186)
    - Portrait of Gräf (Kopf Gräf), 414 / Strret Scene (Straßenszene), 414v, 1914 / 1913-1914 (Box 2, Folder 187)
    - Portrait of Hugo (Porträt Hugo), 415, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 188)
    - Portrait of Oskar Schlemmer (Bildnis Oskar Schlemmer), 416, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 189)
    - Self-Portrait; Double Portrait (Selbstbildnis; Doppelbildnis), 417, 1914-1915 (Box 2, Folder 190)
    - Card Player; Hardt's Son (Kartenspielender Knabe; der Son Hardt), 418 / Reclining Nude with Man's Head (liegender weiblicher Akt mit Männerkopf), 418v, 1914-1915 / 1912 (Box 2, Folder 191)
    - Two Women in a Room (Zwei Mädchen im Zimmer), 419, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 192)
    - Olympia (Olympia), 420, 1914-1915 (Box 2, Folder 193)
    - Self-Portrait (Selbstbildnis), 421, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 194)
    - Portrait of Gerda (Bildnis Gerda), 422, 1914-1926 (Box 2, Folder 195)
    - Gräf and Friend (Gräf und Freund), 423 / Bathers around a Pink Rock (Badende um einen rosa Stein), 423v, 1914 / 1913 (Box 2, Folder 196)
    - Portrait of Botho Gräf, Jena; Music Room (Bildnis Gräf, Jena; Musikzimmer), 424, 1914/1926 (Box 2, Folder 197)
    - Two Friends Conversing (Zwei Freunde im Gespräch), 425 / Dune Landscape with Girl (Dünenlandschaft mit Mädchen), 425v, 1914 / 1913 (Box 2, Folder 198)
    - Farewell; Botho and Hugo (Der Abshied; Botho und Hugo), 426, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 199)
    - Women on the Street (Frauen auf der Straße), 427, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - The Drinker; Self-Portrait (Der Trinker; Selbstbildnis), 428, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Erna with Cigarette (Erna mit Zigarette), 429, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Three Boys in Blue; The Sons of Professor Fehr (Drei Knaben in Blau; die Söhne von Professor Fehr), 430, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Officer and Waitress (Offizier und Kellnerin), 431, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Hussars on Horseback; The Riders (Husarenritt; Die Reiter), 432, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Mounted Artillerymen (Reitende Artilleristen), 433, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Artillerymen in the Shower (Das Soldatenbad), 434, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Self-Portrait as a Soldier (Selbstbildnis als Soldat), 435, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - The Red Tower in Halle (Der Rote Turm in Halle), 436, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Brandenburg Gate, Berlin (Brandenburger Tor, Berlin), 437, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Houses, Bridge, and Traintracks (Häuser, Brücke und Eisenbahngleise), 438, 1915-1916 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Man (Der Mann), 439, 1915/1925 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Women Bathing, Triptych (Badende Frauen, Triptychon), 440, 1915/1925 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Nude at the Mirror (Akt vor dem Spiegel), 441, 1915/1920 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Music Room II (Musikzimmer II), 442, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Dance between the Women (Der Tanz zwischen den Frauen), 443, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Gallows Hill in Jena (Galgenberg in Jena), 444, 1915-1916 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Conservatory (Gewächshaus), 445, 1915-1916 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Gräf's Garden (Garten Gräf in Jena), 446, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Two Strollers in the Park (Zwei Spaziergänger in Parklandschaft), 447, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Sawmill in Königstein (Die Sägemühle in Königstein), 448, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Mill in the Forest (Mühle im Walde), 449, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Man on the Road with Chesnut Trees (Kastanienallee mit Mann), 450, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Taunus Road (Autostrasse im Taunus), 451, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Taunus Fir Trees (Taunusstannen), 452, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Taunus Valley; Small Bridge in the Woods (Tal im Taunus; Landschaft mit kleiner Waldbrücke), 453, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Landscape (Landschaft), 454, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Fruit and White Narcissi (Früchte und weiße Narzissen), 455, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Still Life with Oval Bowl and Flowers (Stilleben mit ovaler Schale und Blumen), 456, 1915-1916 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Portrait of Dr. Kohnstamm (Bildnis Dr. Kohnstamm), 457, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Portrait of Carl Sternheim (Bildnis Carl Sternheim), 458, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Soldier and Girl Between Colorful Curtains (Soldat und Mädchen zwischen bunten Vorhängen), 459, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Bridge into Town (Dorf mit Brücke), 460, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Königstein Street (Straße in Königstein), 461, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Town with Blue Paths (Dorf mit blauen Wegen), 462, 1916/1920 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - View from the Balcony (Blick von Balkon), 463, 1916-1917 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Yellow Tree in the Garden (Gelber Baum in Garten), 464, 1916-1917 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Man in the Woods (Mann im Wald), 465, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Taunus Park, Königstein; Small Taunus Landscape (Taunuspark, Königstein; Kleine Taunuslandschaft), 466, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Königstein with Red Church (Königstein mit roter Kirche), 467, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Villas (Villen), 468, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Königstein Station (Bahnhof Königstein), 469, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Königstein and Railroad Train (Königstein und Eiselbahn), 470, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Frankfurt Cathedral (Frankfurter Dom), 471, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - West Harbor, Frankfurt (Frankfurter Westhafen), 472, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Railroad in Taunus (Eisenbahn im Taunus), 473, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Houses in the Snow (Häuser im Schnee), 474, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Mountain Scene (Die Rüfe), 475, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Königstein Train Station (Bahnhof Königstein), 476, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Blossoming Tuliptree (Blühender Tulpenbaum), 477, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Park; Beech Trees (Park; Buchenwald), 478, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Laburnum Tree; Curved Bay (Goldregenbaum; Runde Bucht), 479, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Portrait of Erna Kirchner (Porträt Erna Kirchner), 480, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Two Cows (Zwei Kühe), 481, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Two Figures, Sketch (Zwei Figuren, Skizze), 482, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Stil Life with Candle (Stilleben mit Kerze), 483, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Portrait of Mrs. Spengler (Kopf Frau Dr. Spengler), 484, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Professor Julius Schaxell (Professor Julius Schaxell), 485, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - The Couple (Paar), 486, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Morning Coffee (Morgenkaffee), 487, 1917/1920 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - The Patient's Bath (Bad des Kranken), 488, 1917/1920 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Flowers and a Head of a Man (Männerkopf mit Blumen), 489, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Blossoming Plants; Flower Still Life (Blühende Pflanze; Blumenstilleben), 490, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Man Seated in Park Chair (Sitzender Mann auf Parkbank), 491, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Seated Couple (Paar, sitzend), 492, 1917/1920 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Female Portrait (Frauenporträt), 493, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Portrait of Eberhad Grisebach (Porträt Eberhard Grisebach), 494, 1917/1920 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Portrait of the Poet Frank (Bildnis des Dichters Frank), 495, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Self-Portrait as a Sick Man (Selbstbildnis als Kranker), 496, 1917/1920 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - The Visit; Mrs. Binswanger (Der Besuch; Frau Binswager), 497, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - The Javanese (Der Janaver), 498, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Dr. Binswanger in Mountain Landscape (Dr. Binswanger vor Berglandschaft), 499, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Portrait of Erna (Kopf Erna), 500, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Cyclamen at Christmastime (Alpenveilchen zu Weihnachten), 501, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 75)